<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.2/docbookx.dtd">

<book lang="en">
	<bookinfo>
		<title>iDART User Guide</title>
		<author>
			<firstname>v3.0,</firstname>
			<othername>August</othername>
			<surname>2007</surname>
		</author>
		<authorinitials>VA2</authorinitials>


	</bookinfo>
	<chapter>
		<title>Welcome to the iDART Pharmacy Tool</title>
		<simpara>
			iDART (which stands for the Intelligent Dispensing of
			Antiretroviral Treatment) is a tool designed to help
			pharmacists and pharmacy assistants with the monthly
			dispensing of antiretroviral drugs. iDART is designed in the
			context of a resource constrained environment, the public
			health sector in South Africa. iDART seeks to address many
			of the problems typical of this type of environment. The
			development of iDART was the result of collaboration work
			between Cell-Life and the Desmond Tutu HIV Centre, in Cape
			Town, South Africa. iDART is an open source project and the
			source code can be downloaded from
			http://idart.Cell-Life.org. It is released under GPL, so
			please feel free to distribute this program under its
			license agreement. Any thoughts or comments would be greatly
			appreciated. Please send these to idart@cell-life.org.za.
		</simpara>

	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>How To Get Help</title>
		<simpara>
			This section explains how the help system (online help and
			manual) is organized, and also introduces the Cell-Life
			Helpdesk.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>About This Manual</title>
			<simpara>
				This manual is a printed version of the online help
				included with the iDART Pharmacy Tool. To access the
				online help, select Launch Help from the main screen.
				The Help Browser will open. It looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/help.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>help browser</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>The Cell-Life Helpdesk</title>
			<simpara>
				The Cell-Life Helpdesk is available between 9am and 5pm,
				Monday to Friday. If you have a problem with the system
				that you cannot solve using the documentation provided,
				please feel free to call us. iDART is a chaptericipatory
				design project. This means that all comments from our
				users are very important, and are often used to guide
				the design of the system. If you call the helpdesk with
				a specific problem, try to call while sitting in front
				of your computer with iDART loaded, as we will usually
				want to talk you through the task you are performing. If
				this isn't possible, have a pen and paper ready. The
				helpdesk can be reached by:
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Calling +21 21 469 1111, Monday to Friday, 9am
						to 5pm
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>Emailing iDART@Cell-Life.org.za</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Features of the iDART Pharmacy Tool</title>
		<simpara>
			iDART was developed in conjunction with the Desmond Tutu HIV
			Centre as a result of a doctor’s requests for a solution to
			help manage and monitor ARV stock control and patient
			therapy dispensing. The challenges identified by the doctor
			which Cell-Life has addressed included:
		</simpara>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					A need to monitor ARV stock levels at any given time
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					A need to be alerted whenever a specific drug level
					was low
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					A need to be notified when any drugs were about to
					expire
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					A need to be notified when patients defaulted on
					treatment collection
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					A need to have an electronic patient history
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					A need to help manage large numbers of patient
					numbers on ART simply and effectively
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					A need to monitor a patients packaging, dispensing
					and monitoring of drugs
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					A need to reduce costs associated with dispensing
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					A need to save time in the process of report
					creation
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<sect1>
			<title>Key benefits of the iDART system:</title>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Accurate tracking of patient treatment
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Comprehensive patient history to treatment
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Accurate ARV stock control management
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Time saving of pharmacy dispensing through
						faster processing
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Reduces and identifies loss of ARVs
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Operates through clearly identifiable,
						multi-lingual bar-coded labels which are created
						for each and every drug and patient package
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>The Technology</title>
			<simpara>
				iDART is developed using open-source technologies and
				has been developed to run on any windows or linux based
				platform, allowing users to access and operate the
				system in a familiar and easy to use way. The choice for
				using open-source software is that there are no
				proprietary licensing costs associated with the use of
				the software. The use of open-source also allows for
				people to take the software for free and use it at their
				sites should they have the necessary skills to manage
				its operation. Each iDART installation operates with a
				barcode label printer connected to the PC which allows
				for each and every drug which is packaged to be clearly
				labelled. The labels which are printed upon dispensing
				can also be created in a range of languages depending on
				the ART site. The labels make for easy drug information
				and label packaging and eradicate many of the errors
				that occur through handwritten dosage instructions.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>The Reporting Tool</title>
			<simpara>
				One of the more important functions of iDART is in the
				various reports that the software makes available. The
				reports range from basic stock control management and
				monitoring reports to specific patient defaulter lists
				which allow for the easy management and follow-up of
				patients. iDART also keeps the entire patient history of
				a patient in its database and allows for accurate
				tracking of patients receiving treatment from ART sites.
				It is important to note that Cell-Life believe strongly
				in addressing the needs of each specific site and the
				technology used is flexible enough to include numerous
				other reports. Cell-Life believe that the technology
				implemented needs to assist the existing processes in
				place at sites and therefore looks to adapt the
				technology to best suit these needs.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Down Referral or Decanting to remote clinics</title>
			<simpara>
				One of the great features of iDART is that it also
				allows for the decanting of packages to remote clinics
				and dispensaries that do not hold stock of ARVs. iDART
				allows a central ART site or pharmacy to prepare
				packages for a patients belonging to remote clinics and
				will trace the entire process until the patient collects
				their drugs. Feedback is then provided via the network
				to the central pharmacy to signal that the package was
				collected and the pharmacist is then allowed to package
				drugs for the patient in the next month. For more
				information on the decanting system please see the
				Cell-Life website. If you have any further queries on
				iDART please visit our website at www.Cell-Life.org or
				call 021 469 1111.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>System Overview</title>
		<simpara>
			This section provides a short description of the function of
			iDART, and shows how the tool can be used in a pharmacy that
			dispenses antiretroviral drugs.
		</simpara>

		<simpara>
			iDart allows ARVs to be pre-packaged for collection by
			patients at a later time. The packaged drugs may either be
			collected at the pharmacy or at a remote clinic. iDART also
			allows users to dispense ARVs immediately to patients at a
			pharmacy.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Pre-packaging ARVs for patients</title>
			<simpara>
				For quick dispensing, iDART allows the pharmacist to
				pre-package a patient's ARVs. The patient may then
				collect their pre-packaged ARVs at the pharmacy or at a
				remote clinic. The date on which the ARVs were
				pre-packaged is recorded by iDART to assist with the
				tracking of the packages.
			</simpara>

			<sect2>
				<title>Collection at the pharmacy</title>
				<simpara>
					If the patient collects the packaged ARVs at the
					pharmacy, the date on which the package is collected
					as well as the date on which the package leaves the
					pharmacy are recorded as the current day.
				</simpara>

			</sect2>
			<sect2>
				<title>Collection at the local clinic</title>
				<simpara>
					Before a patient can collect the packaged ARVs at
					the local clinic, the packaged ARVs need to be
					transported from the pharmacy to the remote/local
					clinic. The date on which the packaged ARVs leave
					the pharmacy is recorded. The packaged drugs are
					then transported to the clinic. The clinic
					eventually receives the packaged ARVs and this date
					is recorded. Finally, when the patient arrives to
					collect his/her packaged ARVs, the date for
					collection is recorded.
				</simpara>

			</sect2>
		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>
				Dispensing to patients at the pharmacy immediately
			</title>
			<simpara>
				If a patient arrives at the pharmacy to collect his/her
				ARVs and the ARVs have not been pre-packaged, iDART
				allows the pharmacist to package and dispense the
				required ARVs immediately. In this case, the date the
				package was packed, the date the package left the
				pharmacy and the date the package was picked up will all
				be recorded as the same day.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Remote Dispensing Feature</title>
			<simpara>
				This section provides a more detailed description of the
				remote dispensing feature in iDART.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Generally, ART consists of a monthly supply of 3
				different types of drugs. These 3 drugs need to be taken
				together. While it is customary for a pharmacist to
				dispense directly to a patient, iDART allows for
				pharmacist to create packages for each individual under
				their responsibility, at a central pharmacy. Labels are
				printed for each of the 3 drugs in the package, and each
				label has a reference to the individual patient. The
				pharmacist can then use a courier service to distribute
				the months supply to a remote rural or semi-rural
				clinic. It is at this clinic that the patient visits on
				a monthly basis to pick up their medications. In
				addition to the remote packaging of ARVs, iDART also
				allows for the direct dispensing of ARVs to a patient.
				Since there are two separate locations in the physical
				infrastructure, iDART consists of two separate
				applications. The first of these resides at the central
				pharmacy. The second application is housed at a service
				point or ARV site, where patients collect their
				medication from a nurse. Since both applications access
				the same database, the responsible pharmacist can assess
				each site that receives drugs from the central store, as
				well as assess all patients monitored on the system.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/Drug_Tracking_-_4_Points_in_Time.jpg"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>
							Drug_Tracking_-_4_Points_in_Time
						</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Since the drugs are couriered to remote areas, it is
				very important for the responsible pharmacist to know
				the location of drugs at all stages of the distribution.
				For this reason, the packages are tracked at 4 specific
				times along the supply chain. Tracking normally happens
				by using a handheld barcode scanner. The first time we
				store information about the packaged drugs is when the
				package is first created. In other words, the time when
				the pharmacist has placed the 3 different drugs into a
				plastic package is recorded. The second time the package
				is tracked is when it leaves the pharmacy. The
				pharmacist scans out the package. When this happens, we
				know that the drugs are now in transit to the destined
				remote clinic. The third time the package is tracked is
				when it arrives at the remote clinic. The nurse working
				at this facility is responsible for receiving the
				packaged drugs from the driver, and scanning in the
				packages as a receipt of their arrival. The final time
				the package is tracked is when the patient visits the
				remote clinic to pick up their monthly supply of ARV.
				The package is then scanned out. By scanning this out, a
				feedback mechanism is created. In other words, the
				pharmacist can obtain the location and status of the
				packages between dispensing and patient pickup.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/iDart_Overview_Diagram2.jpg" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>iDart_Overview_Diagram2</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>
			Getting Started: Updating Pharmacy Details And Adding Drugs,
			Stock, Doctors, Patients and their Prescriptions
		</title>
		<simpara>
			The Basic Concepts section describes tasks you will need to
			perform to set up the system for your pharmacy. First, the
			pharmacy's details (such as address, telephone number etc)
			must be entered. Then, the ARV drugs that will be dispensed
			to patients (such as Efavirenz 200mg Capsules, Kaletra
			Solution etc) must be added. Once the drugs have been added,
			the stock levels for each drug must be recorded. If you
			would like iDART to store regimen information, you will also
			need to define the groups of ARV drugs that can be
			prescribed as regimen 1A, 1B or 2.
		</simpara>

		<simpara>
			Patients must be added next, followed by the doctors who
			will prescribe drugs to the patients. Existing prescriptions
			for the patients must then be recorded.
		</simpara>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>The Pharmacy</title>
		<simpara>
			The system stores the pharmacy's name, address and phone
			number as well as the name of the pharmacist in charge. This
			information is printed on package and drug labels. In
			addition, the names of the pharmacist and pharmacy assistant
			are printed on all iDART reports.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Updating the Pharmacy's Details</title>
			<simpara>
				To update the pharmacy's information, log into the
				system and select General Admin from the main screen. A
				new screen, the General Admin Screen, will appear. From
				this screen, select Update the Pharmacy's Details in the
				Pharmacy Admin section. The Pharmacy Info screen will
				appear. It looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/UpdatePharmacyDetails.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>UpdatePharmacyDetails.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To change any of the details, click in the text box, and
				edit or delete the existing text. The label preview will
				change to reflect your changes. The name of the Head
				Pharmacist will appear on all labels, and on all
				reports. The name of the Pharmacy Assistant, if set,
				will appear on all reports. When you are finished, click
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				. To clear all the text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving any of your
				changes, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>


		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>ARV Drugs</title>
		<simpara>
			The system stores all the ARV drugs that will be given to
			patients. The drug is referenced by its name, which should
			therefore include the abbreviation and strength. For
			example, you might have [d4t] Stavudine 30mg. You need to
			specify the chemical compounds in the drug, fill in the pack
			size, and select the form (tablets, solution etc) as this
			determines the dosage instructions that will be printed on
			the drug label. You can optionally specify a standard dosage
			for the drug. Before the existing stock of a drug can be
			recorded, it must be added as shown in this section. If you
			are unsure about drug attributes, try looking at the example
			with fields filled in, found in the Adding Drugs section.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Adding Drugs</title>
			<simpara>
				Drugs are added using the Add Drug screen. To add a
				drug, log into the system and select
				<emphasis role="strong">General Admin</emphasis>
				from the main screen. A new screen, the
				<emphasis role="strong">General Admin Screen</emphasis>
				, will appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Add a new Drug</emphasis>
				. The Add a New Drug screen will appear. It looks like
				this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/AddDrug.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>AddDrug.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To start, fill in the drug name in the Drug Name field.
				This should include the drug's abbreviation (for ARV
				drugs), full name and strength. An example is [d4t]
				Stavudine 30mg. Note that duplicate drug names are not
				allowed in iDART Next, fill in the drug's chemical
				composition. Select one or more chemical compounds from
				the table on the right hand side, and fill in their
				strength (in mg or mg/ml) by clicking in the strength
				column and entering the value. If the chemical compound
				you want to select is not in the list, you will need to
				add it to the database using the Add Chemical Compound
				button. Please be aware that this should only be done if
				you are absolutely sure you want to add the chemical
				compound. You will be asked to enter you password to
				confirm. Now, fill in the other fields, making sure you
				fill in all fields marked with * as these are
				compulsory. Standard dosage is not compulsory, but if
				you do fill in a standard dosage for a drug you can
				always change this for individual prescriptions. Here is
				an example with all the fields filled in:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/AddDrugFilledIn.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>AddDrugFilledIn.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				When you are finished, click
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				to add the drug. To clear all the text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving the drug, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Updating a Drug's Information</title>
			<simpara>
				Drugs are updated using the Update an Existing Drug
				screen. To update a drug, select
				<emphasis role="strong">General Admin</emphasis>
				from the main screen. A new screen, the General Admin
				Screen, will appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Update an Existing Drug's Information
				</emphasis>
				. The Update an Existing Drug screen will appear. It
				looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/UpdateDrug.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>UpdateDrug.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To get the drug's current information, you should use
				the drug search. For more information about using the
				drug search, please see Using the Drug Search. Once the
				information for an existing drug is displayed, you can
				edit this information. Ensure that at least the fields
				marked with * are filled. All other fields are optional,
				but recommended. The text in the Drug Name field will be
				printed on the drug label during dispensing, so be sure
				to include the strength, form and quantity, as is shown
				in the example above. An example is [d4t] Stavudine
				30mg. Note that duplicate drug names are not allowed in
				iDART. You should also make sure the drug's chemical
				composition is correct. To change the chemical
				composition, select one or more chemical compounds from
				the table on the right hand side, and fill in their
				strength (in mg or mg/ml) by clicking in the strength
				column and entering the value. If the chemical compound
				you want to select is not in the list, you will need to
				add it to the database using the Add Chemical Compound
				button. Please be aware that this should only be done if
				you are absolutely sure you want to add the chemical
				compound. You will be asked to enter you password to
				confirm.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				When you are finished, click
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				to change the drug's information. To clear all the text
				fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without changing the drug
				information, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Stock</title>
		<simpara>
			When the system is first set up, all the stock batches of
			ARV drugs at the pharmacy must be recorded. Tin is only done
			once. After this, stock arrivals must also be recorded each
			time they occur. Careful recording of stock allows the
			system to maintain accurate stock levels and produce stock
			reports.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Adding Stock</title>
			<simpara>
				The Stock Arrives screen must be used to add the stock
				to the database. Before adding stock of a drug, it is
				important to add the drug itself using the Add a New
				Drug screen, if this has not already been done. For more
				information on this, see Adding Drugs. It is also
				important that the distribution clinic for which the
				stock is intended has been added. For more information
				on this, see Adding Distribution Clinics. To add stock,
				log into the system and select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Stock &amp; Dispensing
				</emphasis>
				from the main screen. A new screen, the Stock Control
				Screen, will appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Stock Arrives</emphasis>
				. The Stock Arrives at Pharmacy screen will appear. It
				looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/StockArrives.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>StockArrives.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				This screen displays a list of all the stock being added
				during the current session. For each batch, the user
				must perform the following steps:
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Click Add Stock on the Stock Arrives at Pharmacy
						Screen (above). The Add Stock screen appears. It
						looks like this:
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/StockArrivesAddDrug.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>StockArrivesAddDrug.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Use the Drug Search button to select the drug
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Fill in the batch information in the lower half
						of the screen
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				When you are finished, click
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				to add the stock batch. To clear all the text fields,
				press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving the stock batch,
				press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				. You will now be returned to the Stock Arrives at
				Pharmacy screen. If you have successfully added stock,
				it should appear in the list on this screen. If it has
				not appeared, or to add another batch of this or another
				drug, click Add Stock and repeat the steps above.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you have made a mistake and wish to remove a batch
				from the list of batches to be saved, click the batch in
				the stock list to select it, and click the
				<emphasis role="strong">Remove Selected Batch</emphasis>
				button.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Once you have finished adding all the stock you wish to
				add in this session, click
				<emphasis role="strong">Submit</emphasis>
				to save the stock. If you want to leave this screen
				without saving anything (all the stock you entered will
				be lost), click
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				When you click Submit, a Stock Receipt report can
				generated, showing all the stock that has been entered
				on this day. You should check the Stock Receipt Report
				to be sure that the stock arrival has been recorded
				correctly. You can then print or save this report. See
				the section Printing and Saving Reports for further
				information about this.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Doctors</title>
		<simpara>
			All the doctors who will prescribe ARV drugs to the patients
			being served by this pharmacy (and any remote clinics
			attached to it) must be added to the system.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Adding Doctors</title>
			<simpara>
				Doctors are added using the Add A New Doctor screen.
				From the main screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">General Admin</emphasis>
				. A new screen, the General Admin Screen, will appear.
				From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Add a new Doctor</emphasis>
				. The Add a New Doctor screen will appear. It looks like
				this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/AddDoctor.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>AddDoctor.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Fill in at least the doctor's name and surname (the
				compulsory fields, marked with
				<emphasis role="strong">
					). The other fields are recommended, but not
					required. When you are finished, click *Save
				</emphasis>
				to add the doctor. To clear all the text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving the doctor, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Updating a Doctor's Information</title>
			<simpara>
				A doctor's information can be updated using the Update
				an Existing Doctor screen. From the main screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">General Admin</emphasis>
				. A new screen, the General Admin Screen, will appear.
				From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Update an Existing Doctor's Details
				</emphasis>
				. The Update an Existing Doctor screen will appear. It
				looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/UpdateDoctor.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>UpdateDoctor.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Fill in at least the doctor's name and surname (the
				compulsory fields, marked with
				<emphasis role="strong">
					). The other fields are recommended, but not
					required. When you are finished, click *Save
				</emphasis>
				to save your changes to the doctor. To clear all the
				text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving the doctor, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>


		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Patients</title>
		<simpara>
			The system stores detailed information on each patient
			receiving ARV drugs from the pharmacy and any remote clinics
			its supplies. This includes personal information as well as
			information on allergies that may influence the drugs the
			patient can take. Most of this information is not
			compulsory. The amount of information you collect from
			patients, and record, is left up to you. The fields marked
			with *, however, are compulsory.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Adding Patients</title>
			<simpara>
				Patients are added though the
				<emphasis role="strong">Add a New Patient</emphasis>
				screen. To add a patient, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Patient Admin</emphasis>
				from the main screen. The Patient Admin screen will
				appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Add a New Patient to the System
				</emphasis>
				. This will bring up the Add a New Patient screen. It
				looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/AddPatient.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>AddPatient.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				First, you should enter the Patient ID. This is used to
				uniquely identify the patient, so no two patients are
				allowed to have the same Patient ID. If you do try to
				save a patient with the same Patient ID a patient
				already in the system, you will be asked to change the
				Patient ID before you can save. The other restriction on
				the Patient ID relates to its l, which determines the l
				of the barcodes printed on labels. The maximum length of
				a Patient ID that contains a mixture of letters and
				numbers is 10 characters. For Patient IDs consisting
				only of numbers, the maximum length is 18 characters.
				Once you have chosen a Patient ID, you must enter at
				least the patient's first name, surname, date of birth,
				distribution clinic and account status. These fields,
				marked with *, are compulsory; the other fields are
				optional but recommended. Note that you cannot enter the
				patient's age; this is calculated from the date of
				birth.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The patient's next appointment date can also be set or
				updated from this screen. If there is no upcoming
				appointment for the patient, a new appointment can be
				added. If the patient has an upcoming appointment, the
				date of this appointment can be changed.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you want to save the patient and be taken to the Add
				Initial Prescription screen to capture a prescription
				for this patient, choose
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Create Initial Prescription
				</emphasis>
				. If you want to save the patient, but do not want to
				capture a prescription for this patient at this time,
				choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To clear all the text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving the patient, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Updating a Patient's Information</title>
			<simpara>
				To update a patient, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Patient Admin</emphasis>
				from the main screen. The Patient Admin screen will
				appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Update an Existing Patient's Details
				</emphasis>
				. This will bring up the Update an Existing Patient
				screen. It looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/UpdatePatient.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>UpdatePatient.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				First, you should enter the Patient ID. You can type
				this in and press enter, scan the information label for
				a patient using a barcode scanner, or use the patient
				search to do this. For more information on entering
				Patient IDs using the patient search, please see Using
				the Patient Search.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Once you have entered a patient ID, the system will
				bring up the information it has stored about this
				patient. You can now edit this information. The fields
				marked with * are compulsory; the other fields are
				optional but recommended. The patient's next appointment
				date can also be set or updated from this screen. If
				there is no upcoming appointment for the patient, a new
				appointment can be added. If the patient has an upcoming
				appointment, the date of this appointment can be
				changed.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you want to save the changed patient information and
				be taken to the Update Prescription screen to update the
				prescription for this patient, choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Update Prescription</emphasis>
				. If you want to save the changed patient information,
				but do not want to update the prescription for this
				patient at this time, choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To clear all the text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving the changed patient
				information, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>


		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Merging Duplicate Patients</title>
			<simpara>
				To merge two patient records that you have determined
				belong to the same patient, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Patient Admin</emphasis>
				from the main screen. The Patient Admin screen will
				appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Merge Patients</emphasis>
				. This will bring up the Merge Patients screen. It looks
				like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/MergePatient.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>MergePatient.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				First, you should enter the Patient ID of the primary
				patient. This is the patient whose Patient ID you wish
				to use for the merged patient after the merge. You can
				type this in and press enter, scan the information label
				for a patient using a barcode scanner, or use the
				patient search to do this. For more information on
				entering Patient IDs using the patient search, please
				see Using the Patient Search.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Once you have entered a patient ID, the system will
				bring up the information it has stored about this
				patient in the Primary Patient area, as shown in the
				screenshot below:
			</simpara>
			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/MergePatientLeft.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>MergePatientLeft.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				You should now load up the secondary patient by entering
				the patient ID in the same way. The secondary patient's
				ID will be recorded as an old ID of the primary patient.
				All packages, prescriptions, appointments and episodes
				from the secondary patient record will be removed from
				this patient record, and will now belong to the merged
				patient.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Once both the primary and secondary patients are loaded,
				the merge patient details will be filled in. The screen
				will look like this:
			</simpara>
			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/MergePatientFilledIn.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>MergePatientFilledIn.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				You can edit the basic information about the merge
				patient that is shown in the text fields on this screen.
				If both secondary and primary patients have a valid next
				apointment, you should also choose one appoinment to
				keep. The one you do not choose will be marked as
				invalid, and the patient will appear on the Patients
				Expected On A Day report for that appointment date.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Be warned that you cannot undo a patient merge! If you
				are sure you want to save the patient merge, choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				. You will be asked for your password to confirm the
				merge, then taken to the Update Patient screen to view
				and update all details for the merged patient.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To clear all the text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving the patient merge,
				press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>


		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Patients' Prescriptions</title>
		<simpara>
			The ARV prescription for a patient must be stored in the
			system. Information about the prescription, such as the
			doctor who prescribed the drugs and the clinical stage of
			the patient, as well as a list of all the drugs on the
			prescription, is stored. When a prescription changes, for
			example due to a renewal or the the patient displaying an
			adverse reation to one of the drugs, this must be recorded
			in a prescription update.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Adding Patients' Prescriptions</title>
			<simpara>
				Before you add a prescription for a patient, you need
				to: Add the doctor responsible for this prescription
				(see Adding Doctors) Add the drugs that will be
				specified by this prescription (see Adding Drugs) Add
				the stock batches for each drug (see Adding Stock) Add
				the patient's distribution clinic (see Adding
				Distribution Clinics) if it is not already loaded Add
				the patient (see Adding Patients)
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To add the initial prescription, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Patient Admin</emphasis>
				from the main screen. The Patient Admin screen will
				appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Add/Update a Patient's Prescription
				</emphasis>
				. This will bring up the Patient's Prescription screen.
				It looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/AddPrescription.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>AddPrescription.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To tell the system which patient this prescription is
				for, enter the Patient ID. You can type this into the
				Patient ID text box, or you can select Patient Search to
				search for IDs. For more information about the Patient
				Search feature, please see Using the Patient Search.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Once you have entered the ID of a patient in the system,
				check that the patient's first name, surname and age are
				correct. This information is in greyed-out boxes as you
				cannot edit patient information here. See Updating
				Patient Information if you need to change information
				about a patient already on the system.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Select the patient's doctor from the drop-down list. Get
				the list to drop down by clicking the arrow on the right
				hand side of the box,and click an entry in the list to
				select it. If you wish to add a new doctor, click the
				button next to the drop-down list of doctors, and add
				the doctor here. Select the prescription duration in the
				same way, and also the clinical stage and weight if you
				would like to record this information.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The notes field is an optional area where you can record
				any information about the patient that you would like
				displayed when you are dispensing to this patient. To
				add notes, just click in the field and type your notes.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				You can now add drugs to the prescription.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you wish to add all drugs from a drug group, select
				the drug group from the drop-down list. The drugs will
				automatically be added to the list of drugs on this
				patient's prescription.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To add drugs manually, do the following for each drug
				you wish to add:
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						To add a drug, select Add Drug to this
						Prescription. The add a Drug screen will appear.
						It looks like this:
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/AddDrugToScript.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>AddDrugToScript.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						To add a drug to the prescription, you should
						use the drug search. For more information about
						the drug search, please see Using the Drug
						Search.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Check the information about the drug (such as
						its name and strength) is correct. Enter the
						number of units to take in each dose, and select
						the number of doses per day from the drop-down
						list.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						When you are finished, click
						<emphasis role="strong">
							Add to Prescription
						</emphasis>
						to add the drug to the prescription. The drug
						will appear in the list of drugs on this
						prescription. To clear all the text fields,
						press
						<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
						. To leave the screen without adding the drug,
						press
						<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
						. You will be returned to the Patient's
						Prescription screen.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				If you need to remove a drug from the drugs list, click
				the entry in the Drugs list to select it, and then click
				the
				<emphasis role="strong">Remove Selected Drug</emphasis>
				button. The system will ask you whether you wish to
				remove this drug - select
				<emphasis role="strong">Yes</emphasis>
				to remove the drug, or
				<emphasis role="strong">No</emphasis>
				if you do not wish to remove the drug. You can also
				change the order in which the drugs appear on the
				prescription (and hence the order in which the labels
				will print when the prescription is dispensed) by
				selecting the drug you wish to remove and clicking the
				up or down arrow buttons found on either side of the
				drugs list.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you want to save the prescription and be taken to the
				Patient Packaging screen to dispense the prescription
				now, choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Dispense Now</emphasis>
				. If you want to save the prescription, but do not want
				to dispense it at this time, choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To clear all the text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving the prescription,
				press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Updating Patients' Prescriptions</title>
			<simpara>
				To update a patient's prescription, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Patient Admin</emphasis>
				from the main screen. The Patient Admin screen will
				appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Add/Update a Patient's Prescription
				</emphasis>
				. This will bring up the Patient's Prescription screen.
				It looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/AddPrescription.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>AddPrescription.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To tell the system which patient's prescription you wish
				to update, enter the Patient ID. You can type this into
				the Patient ID text box, or you can select Patient
				Search to search for IDs. For more information about the
				Patient Search feature, please see Using the Patient
				Search. Once you have entered the ID of a patient in the
				system, the fields on the Patient's Prescription screen
				should be filled with information from the patient's
				current prescription, as in the example below:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/UpdatePrescription.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>UpdatePrescription.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Select the reason you are updating the prescription from
				the drop-down list. Get the list to drop down by
				clicking the arrow on the right hand side of the box,
				and click an entry in the list to select it. Also check
				that the patient's first name, surname and age are
				correct. This information is in greyed-out boxes as you
				cannot edit patient information here. See Updating
				Patient Information if you need to change information
				about a patient already on the system.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you wish to change the patient's doctor, select a
				different doctor from the drop-down list. Get the list
				to drop down by clicking the arrow on the right hand
				side of the box, and click an entry in the list to
				select it. If you wish to add a new doctor, click the
				button next to the drop-down list of doctors, and add
				the doctor here. Select the prescription duration in the
				same way, and also the clinical stage and weight if you
				would like to record this information.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The notes field is an optional area where you can record
				any information about the patient that you would like
				displayed when you are dispensing to this patient. To
				add notes, just click in the field and type your notes.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you wish to add all drugs from a drug group, select
				the drug group from the drop-down list. The drugs will
				automatically be added to the list of drugs on this
				patient's prescription.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you wish to add drugs to the prescription manually,
				do the following for each drug you wish to add.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To add drugs manually, do the following for each drug
				you wish to add:
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						To add a drug, select Add Drug to this
						Prescription. The add a Drug screen will appear.
						It looks like this:
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/AddDrugToScript.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>AddDrugToScript.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						To add a drug to the prescription, you should
						use the drug search. For more information about
						the drug search, please see Using the Drug
						Search.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Check the information about the drug (such as
						its name and strength) is correct. Enter the
						number of units to take in each dose, and select
						the number of doses per day from the drop-down
						list.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						When you are finished, click
						<emphasis role="strong">
							Add to Prescription
						</emphasis>
						to add the drug to the prescription. The drug
						will appear in the list of drugs on this
						prescription. To clear all the text fields,
						press
						<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
						. To leave the screen without adding the drug,
						press
						<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
						. You will be returned to the Patient's
						Prescription screen.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				If you need to remove a drug from the drugs list, click
				the entry in the Drugs list to select it, and then click
				the
				<emphasis role="strong">Remove Selected Drug</emphasis>
				button. The system will ask you whether you wish to
				remove this drug - select
				<emphasis role="strong">Yes</emphasis>
				to remove the drug, or
				<emphasis role="strong">No</emphasis>
				if you do not wish to remove the drug. You can also
				change the order in which the drugs appear on the
				prescription (and hence the order in which the labels
				will print when the prescription is dispensed) by
				selecting the drug you wish to remove and clicking the
				up or down arrow buttons found on either side of the
				drugs list.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you want to save the prescription and be taken to the
				Patient Packaging screen to dispense the prescription
				now, choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Dispense Now</emphasis>
				. If you want to save the prescription, but do not want
				to dispense it at this time, choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To clear all the text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving the prescription,
				press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Pharmacy Users</title>
		<simpara>
			The system stores information on who at the pharmacy is
			allowed to log in to the system. This information is limited
			to a username and a password, which will be required each
			time the user logs in to the system.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Manage Pharmacy Users</title>
			<simpara>
				The Manage Pharmacy Users screen allows the currently
				logged in user to
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>Change their password</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>Add a new iDART user</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				To access this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">General Admin</emphasis>
				from the main screen. A new screen, the General Admin
				Screen, will appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Manage Pharmacy Users</emphasis>
				. The Manage Pharmacy Users screen will appear. It looks
				like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/UpdateIDartUser.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>UpdateIDartUser.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<sect2>
				<title>To add a new user:</title>
				<simpara>
					Select the
					<emphasis role="strong">
						Add New iDART User
					</emphasis>
					radio button. Enter a username for the new user in
					the Username field, and then enter their password in
					the password and confirm password fields. The text
					in the two fields must be identical. Note that
					characters in passwords appear as * symbols when
					entered, to prevent anyone from seeing the password
					being typed.
				</simpara>

				<simpara>
					When you are finished, click
					<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
					to add the new user. To clear all the text fields,
					press
					<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
					. To leave the screen without adding a new user,
					press
					<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
					.
				</simpara>

			</sect2>
			<sect2>
				<title>
					To change the password of the currently logged in
					user:
				</title>
				<simpara>
					Select the Change Your Password radio button. Enter
					your old password, then enter you new password in
					the New Password and Confirm New Password fields.
					The text in the last two fields must be identical.
					Note that characters in passwords appear as *
					symbols when entered, to prevent anyone from seeing
					the password being typed. When you are finished,
					click *Save* to add the new user. To clear all the
					text fields, press
					<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
					. To leave the screen without adding a new user,
					press
					<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
					.
				</simpara>

			</sect2>
		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Distribution Clinics</title>
		<simpara>
			(Please note that this section is only relevant to versions
			of iDART using the remote dispensing feature)
		</simpara>

		<simpara>
			The place where a patient collects their ARV medication,
			whether this is located in the same building as the pharmacy
			or at a remote clinic, is the patient's distribution clinic.
			Distribution clinics are also relevant to stock, as each
			stock batch is assigned to a distribution clinic.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Adding Distribution Clinics</title>
			<simpara>
				(Please note that this section is only relevant to
				versions of iDART using the remote dispensing feature)
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To add a distribution clinic, log into the system and
				select
				<emphasis role="strong">General Admin</emphasis>
				from the main screen. A new screen, the General Admin
				Screen, will appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Add a New Clinic</emphasis>
				. The Add a New Clinic screen will appear. It looks like
				this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/AddClinic.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>AddClinic.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Fill in at least the clinic name. All other details are
				optional, but recommended.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				When you are finished, click
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				to add the new clinic. To clear all the text fields,
				press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without adding a new clinic, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Updating a Distribution Clinic's Information</title>
			<simpara>
				(Please note that this section is only relevant to
				versions of iDART using the remote dispensing feature)
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To update a clinic's information, select General Admin
				from the main screen. A new screen, the
				<emphasis role="strong">General Admin Screen</emphasis>
				, will appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Update an Existing Clinic's Details
				</emphasis>
				. The Update an Existing Clinic screen will appear. It
				looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/UpdateClinic.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>UpdateClinic.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Enter the clinic name, or use the clinic search to find
				a clinic by selecting
				<emphasis role="strong">Clinic Search</emphasis>
				. This will bring up a list of the clinics currently on
				the system. It looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/ClinicSearch.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>ClinicSearch.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				You can select a clinic by clicking an entry in the
				list. If you enter text in the text box below the list,
				the clinics whose names do not contain the text you have
				entered will be hidden, making it easier to find the
				clinic you are looking for. Once you click a clinic in
				the list, you will be returned to the Update an Existing
				Clinic screen, and information for the clinic you chose
				will be selected. If you do not want to select a clinic
				from the Clinic Search screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				to leave the Clinic Search screen.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Once the information for an existing clinic is
				displayed, you can edit this information. Ensure that at
				least the clinic name is entered. All other details are
				optional, but recommended.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				When you are finished, click
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				to save the new information with the clinic. To clear
				all the text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without changing the information
				for a clinic, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>


		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Drug Groups</title>
		<simpara>Drug groups serve two purposes:</simpara>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					When adding drugs to a new prescription for a
					patient, you can select a drug group and all the
					drugs in the drug group will be added to the
					prescription, speeding the prescription capture
					process.
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					Each drug group is associated with a regimen. This
					means that iDART can count how many patients are on
					each regimen by comparing the  drugs on the
					patients' prescriptions with the drugs in the drug
					group. For this reason, it's important that the drug
					groups are captured accurately.
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<simpara>
			Examples of drug groups that would be associated with
			regimen 1A could be
		</simpara>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					Stavudine 30mg BID, Lamivudine 150mg BID, Efavirenz
					600mg QD
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<simpara>
					Stavudine 40mg BID, Lamivudine 150mg BID, Efavirenz
					600mg QD
				</simpara>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<sect1>
			<title>Add Drug Groups</title>
			<simpara>
				To add a new drug group, select
				<emphasis role="strong">General Admin</emphasis>
				from the main screen. The General Admin screen will
				appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Add a New Drug Group</emphasis>
				. This will bring up the Drug Groups screen. It looks
				like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/AddRegimen.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>AddRegimen.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Enter a name for the new drug group. Then, select the
				regimen that this drug group comprises. Please be
				careful when setting a regimen - a drug group only
				belongs to a regimen when it contains all the drugs
				required for that regimen. Once you have selected the
				drug group, the fields on the Drug Groups screen should
				be filled with the Drug Group's current information, as
				in the example below:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To add drugs to the drug group, do the following for
				each drug you wish to add:
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						To add a drug, select Add Drug to this
						Prescription. The add a Drug screen will appear.
						It looks like this:
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/AddDrugToScript.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>AddDrugToScript.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						To add a drug to the prescription, you should
						use the drug search. For more information about
						the drug search, please see Using the Drug
						Search.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Check the information about the drug (such as
						its name and strength) is correct. Enter the
						number of units to take in each dose, and select
						the number of doses per day from the drop-down
						list.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						When you are finished, click
						<emphasis role="strong">Add to Group</emphasis>
						to add the drug to the drug group. The drug will
						appear in the list of drugs in the drug group.
						To clear all the text fields, press
						<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
						. To leave the screen without adding the drug,
						press
						<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
						. You will be returned to the Drug Groups screen
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				If you need to remove a drug from the Drugs list, click
				the entry in the Drugs list. The system will ask you
				whether you wish to remove this drug - select
				<emphasis role="strong">Yes</emphasis>
				to remove the drug, or
				<emphasis role="strong">No</emphasis>
				if you do not wish to remove the drug.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you want to save the drug group, choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To clear all the text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving the drug group,
				press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Updating Drug Groups</title>
			<simpara>
				To update an existing drug group, select
				<emphasis role="strong">General Admin</emphasis>
				from the main screen. The General Admin screen will
				appear. From this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Update an Existing Group's Details
				</emphasis>
				. This will bring up the Drug Groups screen. It looks
				like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/UpdateRegimen.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>UpdateRegimen.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To select the drug group you wish to update, click the
				<emphasis role="strong">Drug Group Search</emphasis>
				button. Select the drug group, then click Ok.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Once you have selected the drug group, the fields on the
				Drug Groups screen should be filled with the Drug
				Group's current information.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you need to change the regimen that the drugs in this
				drug group comprise, you can do so by selecting a
				different regimen. Please be careful when setting a
				regimen - a drug group only belongs to a regimen when it
				contains all the drugs required for that regimen.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you wish to add drugs to the drug group, do the
				following for each drug you wish to add: * To add a
				drug, select Add Drug to this Prescription. The add a
				Drug screen will appear. It looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/AddDrugToScript.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>AddDrugToScript.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						To add a drug to the prescription, you should
						use the drug search. For more information about
						the drug search, please see Using the Drug
						Search.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Check the information about the drug (such as
						its name and strength) is correct. Enter the
						number of units to take in each dose, and select
						the number of doses per day from the drop-down
						list.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						When you are finished, click
						<emphasis role="strong">Add to Group</emphasis>
						to add the drug to the drug group. The drug will
						appear in the list of drugs in the drug group.
						To clear all the text fields, press
						<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
						. To leave the screen without adding the drug,
						press
						<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
						. You will be returned to the Drug Groups screen
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				If you need to remove a drug from the Drugs list, click
				the entry in the Drugs list. The system will ask you
				whether you wish to remove this drug - select
				<emphasis role="strong">Yes</emphasis>
				to remove the drug, or
				<emphasis role="strong">No</emphasis>
				if you do not wish to remove the drug.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you want to save the drug group, choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To clear all the text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving the drug group,
				press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Packaging and Dispensing</title>
		<simpara>
			This section describes the creation of ARV packages for
			patients, and how to dispense the package to the patient
			either directly, by pre-packing for patients at this
			pharmacy, or by pre-packing for patients at a remote clinic.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Creating Patient ARV Packages</title>
			<simpara>
				This section describes how to create monthly ARV
				packages for patients according to their prescriptions.
				Dispensing the package to the patient, either directly
				from the pharmacy or via a distribution clinic, is
				covered in the two subsequent sections. From the main
				screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Stock &amp; Dispensing
				</emphasis>
				. This will open the Stock Control screen - select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Make Up Drug Packages For Patients
				</emphasis>
				. This will open the Make Up ARV Packages for Patients
				screen, which is shown below:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/MakeUpARVPackages.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>MakeUpARVPackages.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				First, check that the correct dispensing mode is
				selected. You can choose one of:
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						<emphasis role="strong">
							I am creating packages for later pickup
						</emphasis>
						if the drugs will be picked up at another time,
						or at a distribution clinic. The date the
						package was packed will be recorded, but not the
						date it left the pharmacy - this will be
						recorded when the package leaves the pharmacy to
						a patient or to a distribution clinic. See
						Dispensing from a Remote Clinic. You will not
						need to record the adherence information on this
						screen if you are doing this type of dispensing.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						<emphasis role="strong">
							I am dispensing directly to patients
						</emphasis>
						if the patient will take the package now, and
						today's date should be recorded as the date the
						package was packed, left the pharmacy and was
						picked up by the patient. The system will not
						record any further tracking information about
						this package as it will be considered dispensed
						to the patient. You will be able to record
						adherence information for the patient on this
						screen if you are doing this kind of dispensing.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				Both the above options will cause labels for all the
				drugs in the packages to be printed. If you choose
				Create Package for Later, a package cover label will
				also be printed.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Select a distribution clinic from the drop-down list.
				This will bring up a list of all the patients for whom
				ARV packages should be made up. The list includes all
				patients at the selected clinic who have current
				prescriptions.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Select a patient from the list to start making up a
				package for that patient. If you are looking for a
				specific patient, try using the search bar (the text box
				directly below the patient list). Typing a character or
				a few characters in this box will hide the Patient IDs
				in the list that do not contain the character(s) you
				have typed.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Clicking a Patient ID in the list of waiting patients
				will cause information about the patient to come up in
				the Patient Information area, and information about the
				patient's current prescription to come up in the
				Prescription Information area. The drugs that a package
				for this patient should contain will be shown in red in
				the drugs table. At this point, also be aware of notes
				displayed for the patient. If the patient is a child,
				the system will warn you by placing a small icon showing
				a child next to the age field. This icon looks like
				this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/Child_50x43.jpg"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>Child_50x43.jpg</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				You need to dispense at least one of the drugs in the
				list, but you do not have to dispense them all. To
				dispense drugs:
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						You need to select how many months' or weeks'
						supply this package represents from the
						drop-down list. This will allow the system to
						pre-calculate the number of pills to dispense.
						By default, these will come from the batch that
						will expire soonest.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						When the system records a patient as having
						received a package, the patient's next
						appointment date is set according to how many
						months or weeks supply of ARV drugs the package
						contains. If you are dispensing directly to
						patients, the next appointment date will
						therefore be recorded from this screen. In this
						case, you can set the next appointment date in
						the Patient Information section. If you are
						creating packages for later pickup, the next
						appointment date will be set automatically when
						the package is scanned out as it is collected by
						the patient.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						The table of
						<emphasis role="strong">
							Drugs To Dispense in This Package
						</emphasis>
						will automatically be populated, as will the
						<emphasis role="strong">
							Pill Count – Last Package
						</emphasis>
						table. You need to:
					</simpara>
					<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
						<listitem>
							<simpara>
								Fill in accumulated units the patient
								returns with. This information will be
								used to calculate the patient's
								adherence. To fill in a value, click the
								cell in the Accum column of the
								<emphasis role="strong">
									Pill Count – Last Package
								</emphasis>
								table, and type the value. The adherence
								percentage will be caulculated
								immediately
							</simpara>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<simpara>
								Check the total units in hand for each
								drug, which will appear in the In Hand
								column of the
								<emphasis role="strong">
									Drugs To Dispense in This Package
								</emphasis>
								table. This can have two values, which
								you can choose by clicking in the column
								and selecting the value from the
								dropdown list. You can either record
								that the patient has left with the
								number of units you dispensed as well as
								the number of units accumulated (e.g. 1
								pack of 60 pills + 2 pills accumulated),
								or that you did not give the accumulated
								units back to the patient for whatever
								reason, and that they left with just the
								quantity you dispensed (e.g. 1 pack of
								60 pills).
							</simpara>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<simpara>
								If desired, change the number of labels
								to print by clicking the cell in the
								labels column, and changing the value to
								the desired number of labels. You can
								then edit the batch to dispense from, as
								well as the quantity to dispense, by
								clicking the row containing the drug
								information. This will bring up the
								screen below:
							</simpara>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/BatchInfo.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>BatchInfo.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						You can change the quantity (in pills) to
						dispense. To do this, click the row of the batch
						you wish to dispense from, under the column Qty
						to Dispense, and type in the number of pills.
						The drugs are ordered by expiry date, with the
						batch that will expire soonest listed first. You
						can also select how many drug labels you wish to
						print, from the drop-down list in the Labels to
						Print column.To maintain correct stock levels,
						it's important that the containers you put in to
						the package do in fact come from the batch you
						have selected.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Select
						<emphasis role="strong">
							Add Drug to Package
						</emphasis>
						to save the information you have entered. Select
						<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
						if you do not wish to add this drug to the
						package at this time.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				Once you have specified quantities for each drug you
				wish to add, you should specify whether you want the
				dosage quantities on the label to be left blank (eg. for
				paediatric patients where you want to fill in this
				information by hand) and also whether a script summary
				label should be printed. Do this by selecting your
				choices (Yes or No) below the drugs table.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To create the drug package and print the relevant
				labels, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Create Package</emphasis>
				. If you do not want to create a package at this time,
				you can choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Close</emphasis>
				to close the Make Up ARV Packages for Patients screen.
				If you make a mistake with a package and want to redo
				it, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Redo an ARV Package</emphasis>
				. For more information about this, please see Stock,
				Prescription and Package Deletions in this section.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Pre-packaging for patients at this Pharmacy</title>
			<simpara>
				If you are pre-packaging for patients who collect their
				drugs at the pharmacy, the system tracks packages by
				recording two dates:
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>The date the package was packed</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						The date the package was picked up by the
						patient.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				Packages that have been pre-packed must be scanned using
				a barcode scanner as they leave to record the second
				date.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To record a package leaving the pharmacy to be given to
				a patient, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Stock &amp; Dispensing
				</emphasis>
				from the main screen. From the Stock Control screen,
				select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Scan Out Packages To Patients
				</emphasis>
				. This will cause the Distribute ARV Packages screen
				below to open.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/DistributeARVPackages.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>DistributeARVPackages.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				First, select a clinic from the drop-down list. This
				will cause the Package IDs of all the packages waiting
				to leave for this clinic to appear in the list on the
				left. Use a barcode scanner to scan the package IDs of
				the packages that will leave the pharmacy now. Note that
				in the event of problems with scanning, you can type the
				Package IDs in by hand.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				When you have finished scanning, you can choose
				<emphasis role="strong">
					View Report of Packages Dispensed
				</emphasis>
				to see a report of the packages that have left the
				pharmacy today. You can print or save the report -
				please see Printing and Saving Reports for further
				information on this. If you wish to leave this screen
				without seeing a report, you can choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Close</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Pre-packaging for patients at Remote Clinics</title>
			<simpara>
				(Please note that this section is only relevant to
				versions of iDART using the remote dispensing feature)
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you are pre-packaging for patients who collect their
				drugs at remote clinics, the system tracks packages by
				recording four dates:
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>The date the package was packed</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						The date the package left the pharmacy
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						The date the package arrived at the remote
						clinic
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						The date the package was picked up by the
						patient.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				Packages that have been pre-packed must be scanned using
				a barcode scanner as they leave to record the second
				date. The third and fourth dates are recorded when the
				package is scanned at the clinic using the iDART clinic
				application.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To record a package leaving the pharmacy, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Stock &amp; Dispensing
				</emphasis>
				from the main screen. From the Stock Control screen,
				select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Scan Out Packages To Remote Clinic
				</emphasis>
				. This will cause the Distribute ARV Packages screen
				below to open.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/DistributeARVPackages.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>DistributeARVPackages.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				First, select a clinic from the drop-down list. This
				will cause the Package IDs of all the packages waiting
				to leave for this clinic to appear in the list on the
				left. Use a barcode scanner to scan the package IDs of
				the packages that will leave the pharmacy now. Note that
				in the event of problems with scanning, you can type the
				Package IDs in by hand.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				When you have finished scanning, you can choose
				<emphasis role="strong">
					View Report of Packages Dispensed
				</emphasis>
				to see a report of the packages that have left the
				pharmacy today. You can print or save the report -
				please see Printing and Saving Reports for further
				information on this. If you wish to leave this screen
				without seeing a report, you can choose
				<emphasis role="strong">Close</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Adjustments and Deletions</title>
		<sect1>
			<title>Stock, Prescription and Package Deletions</title>
			<simpara>
				You can perform 4 types of deletions in iDART. These
				are:
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						<emphasis role="strong">
							Package Deletions
						</emphasis>
						: Delete the most recent package for a patient,
						for example when the patient fails to collect
						their drug package.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						<emphasis role="strong">
							Single Package Item Deletions
						</emphasis>
						: Delete an item in the most recent package for
						a patient.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						<emphasis role="strong">
							Prescription Deletions
						</emphasis>
						: Delete a patient's incorrectly captured
						prescription, if this prescription has not been
						dispensed
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						<emphasis role="strong">
							Stock Batch Deletions
						</emphasis>
						: Delete an incorrectly captured stock batch, if
						no drugs have been dispensed from this batch
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				All the above deletions require the currently logged in
				user to provide their password before the deletion
				occurs. A log of the deletion is also created, and a
				report showing all logged deletions for a time period
				can be viewed by selecting
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Transaction Log Report
				</emphasis>
				from the Reports screen.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To perform a deletion, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Stock &amp; Dispensing
				</emphasis>
				from the main screen. Then, select Stock,Prescription
				And Package Deletions. You should see the following
				screen:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/RedoARVPackage.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>RedoARVPackage.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<sect2>
				<title>To perform a package deletion:</title>
				<simpara>
					Select the
					<emphasis role="strong">
						Return Uncollected Packages
					</emphasis>
					radio button. Enter a Patient ID, or use the patient
					search to select the patient whose package you want
					to remove. The most recent package for this patient,
					if any, will be shown, as well as the drugs the
					package contains. To remove the package, select
					<emphasis role="strong">
						Remove this Package
					</emphasis>
					. If you do not wish to remove a package at this
					time, select
					<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
					.
				</simpara>

			</sect2>
			<sect2>
				<title>
					To perform a single package item deletion:
				</title>
				<simpara>
					Select the
					<emphasis role="strong">
						Red Single Item in Package
					</emphasis>
					radio button. Enter a Patient ID, or use the patient
					search to select the patient whose package item you
					want to remove. The most recent package for this
					patient, if any, will be shown, as well as the drugs
					the package contains. To remove an accumulated or
					dispensed drug, select the row containing that
					drug's information and click
					<emphasis role="strong">Remove this Drug</emphasis>
					. If you do not wish to remove a package item at
					this time, select
					<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
					.
				</simpara>

			</sect2>
			<sect2>
				<title>To perform a prescription deletion:</title>
				<simpara>
					Select the
					<emphasis role="strong">
						Delete Incorrect Prescription
					</emphasis>
					radio button. Enter a Patient ID, or use the patient
					search to select the patient whose prescription you
					want to remove. Any prescription for this patient
					that can be removed (i.e. has not yet been
					dispensed) will be shown, as well as the drugs on
					the prescription. To remove the prescription, select
					<emphasis role="strong">
						Remove this Prescription
					</emphasis>
					. If you do not wish to remove a prescription at
					this time, select
					<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
					.
				</simpara>

				<simpara>
					Please note that you cannot remove just one drug in
					a prescription - the entire prescription must be
					removed and redone.
				</simpara>

			</sect2>
			<sect2>
				<title>To perform a stock batch deletion:</title>
				<simpara>
					Select the
					<emphasis role="strong">
						Delete Incorrect Stock Batch
					</emphasis>
					radio button. Use the
					<emphasis role="strong">Drug Search</emphasis>
					button to select the drug for which you wish to
					remove a batch. Any batches for this drug that can
					be removed (i.e. has not yet been dispensed) will be
					shown, To remove a batch, click the batch in the
					list and select
					<emphasis role="strong">
						Remove Selected Batch
					</emphasis>
					. If you do not wish to remove a stock batch at this
					time, select
					<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
					.
				</simpara>

			</sect2>
		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Destroying Unusable Stock</title>
			<simpara>
				When stock expires or is thrown away for any other
				reason, this must be recorded in iDART to ensure that
				stock levels remain correct.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To access the Destroy Stock screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Stock &amp; Dispensing
				</emphasis>
				from the main screen. Then, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Destroy Stock</emphasis>
				. You should see the screen below:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/DestroyStock.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>DestroyStock.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				First, select the drug for which you are destroying
				stock using the
				<emphasis role="strong">Drug Search</emphasis>
				button (for more information on this, see Using the Drug
				Search). Any stock batches that are recorded as having
				stock remaining will now be displayed in the Stock
				Information table, ordered with the batch that will
				expire soonest at the top.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Enter a reason for disposal, which will be displayed in
				the transaction log. Then, click once in the row
				displaying information about the batch from which you
				wish to destroy stock, under the column
				<emphasis>Packs To Destroy</emphasis>
				or
				<emphasis>Loose Pills To Destroy</emphasis>
				. You should now be able to type in the number of packs
				and / or loose pills you want to destroy. Note that the
				number of loose pills (or ml, in the case of liquids)
				destroyed must always be less than the number of pills
				(or ml) in a pack. If you wanted to destroy 90 pills of
				a drug with a packsize of 60, for example, you should
				record this as 1 pack and 30 loose pills destroyed.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				When you have finished, click
				<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
				to record the stock destruction. Stock destructions
				require the currently logged in user to provide their
				password before the destructions occurs. A log of the
				destructions is also created, and a report showing all
				logged transactions for a time period can be viewed by
				selecting
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Transaction Log Report
				</emphasis>
				from the Reports screen.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To clear the screen and start over without saving
				anything, click
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without saving anything, click
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Printing Labels</title>
		<simpara>
			This section describes how to print a patient information
			label or an emergency label for a package, a drug in a
			package or a patient. Generally, printing of package and
			drug labels takes place during the creation of packages and
			is not controlled by the user; however this section also
			includes some hints for troubleshooting common problems with
			these automatically generated package and drug labels.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Printing a Custom Label</title>
			<simpara>
				A custom label is a label on which certain information
				(such as the Patient ID, or the dosage of a drug) is
				typed manually by the user, and not generated
				automatically by the system. This type of label is not
				associated with any other transaction in the system,
				such as the preparation of a package - this function
				exists only to allow the user to create custom labels in
				special circumstances. It does not talk to the database
				except to retreive the pharmacy details.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Printing of emergency package cover, drug or patient
				labels takes place from the Print an Emergency Label
				screen. From the main screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Stock Control</emphasis>
				. This will bring up the
				<emphasis role="strong">Stock Control</emphasis>
				screen - from this screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Make up ARV Packages for Patients
				</emphasis>
				. This will bring up the Make up ARV Packages for
				Patients screen. From this screen, select Create
				Emergency Label. The Create Emergency Label screen looks
				like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/PrintEmergencyLabel.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>PrintEmergencyLabel.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				First, select the kind of label you want to print. The
				editable areas are the areas of the label with a gray
				background. Clicking in one of these areas allows you to
				edit the text in this area. Note that for the package
				label, the Package ID will be replaced by the barcode
				representing it, and also printed in plain text below
				the barcode.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Once you have a label that contains all the correct
				information, you can select the number of labels you
				wish to print for this patient from the drop-down box.
				Then, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Print</emphasis>
				to print the label(s). You will be prompted to select a
				printer; do this and press
				<emphasis role="strong">Print</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To clear all the text fields, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				. To leave the screen without printing any labels, press
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Troubleshooting Label Printing</title>
			<simpara>
				Please note that the system is designed to use labels of
				size 3" by 2", and the Zebra range of label printers.
				These instructions apply to this printer, although they
				may still be useful if you have a different label
				printer. Please also note that these instructions are
				for computers running Microsoft Windows XP.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				If you need to be talked through these procedures, or if
				this does not solve your problem, please call the
				Cell-Life iDART help desk (see How to Get Help).
			</simpara>

			<sect2>
				<title>
					Setting your label printer as the default printer:
				</title>
				<simpara>
					Zebra printers seem to work better when set as the
					default printer. This is usually the first thing to
					try when you experience printing problems. To set
					your label printer as the default printer, do the
					following:
				</simpara>

				<simpara>
					Go to Start Programs, then Control Panel. This will
					bring up the Windows control panel. Click on
					Printers and Other Hardware, then View Installed
					Printers And Faxes. This should show all your
					installed printers. Use the right mouse button to
					click on the printer that prints your labels. This
					should bring up a menu – select Set as Default to
					set this printer as your default printer.
				</simpara>

			</sect2>
			<sect2>
				<title>
					Setting the label size for your label printer:
				</title>
				<simpara>
					If your labels are not printing correctly, you may
					need to reset the paper size on your printer. To do
					this, go to Start Programs, then Control Panel. This
					will bring up the Windows control panel. Click on
					Printers and Other Hardware, then View Installed
					Printers And Faxes. This should show all your
					installed printers. Use the right mouse button to
					click on the printer that prints your labels. This
					should bring up a menu - select Properties, one of
					the last items on this menu. You should see the
					printer properties screen. Select Printing
					Preferences. The screen you see should look
					something like this:
				</simpara>

				<simpara>
					<inlinemediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata
								fileref="images/ZebraPrinting.png" align="center" />
						</imageobject>
						<textobject>
							<phrase>ZebraPrinting.png</phrase>
						</textobject>
					</inlinemediaobject>
				</simpara>

				<simpara>
					Click the + sign next to Paper/Output. This will
					show you the paper settings. Click on the paper size
					(blue, underlined text) to change this. Set the
					paper size to 2" x 3".
				</simpara>

			</sect2>
		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Generating Reports</title>
		<simpara>
			This section explains how to produce reports based on the
			data in the database. The reports can then be saved or
			printed, for your own records.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Patient History Report</title>
			<simpara>
				The Patient History Report shows all previous
				prescriptions for a patient, as well as information
				about the prescription. Prescriptions are ordered by
				date.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To see a Patient History Report, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Reports</emphasis>
				from the main screen. This will open the Reports screen.
				From the Reports screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Patient History Report
				</emphasis>
				. The screen below will open:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/ReportPatientHistory.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>ReportPatientHistory.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Select the patient's distribution point from the
				drop-down list. Then, select the patient by Patient ID
				from the list of patients at that clinic. If you want to
				shorten the list, hiding those Patient IDs that do not
				contain a certain series of characters, type the
				characters the Patient ID must contain in the text box
				below the list of Patient IDs. If you are unclear about
				how this works, please see Using the Patient Search,
				which describes a similar method of finding the correct
				Patient ID.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The report will open in a Report Viewer. You can now
				print or save the report. For information about this,
				please see Printing and Saving Reports.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Pepfar Report</title>
			<simpara>
				This report shows similar indicators to those in the
				Monthly Clinic Indicator report, but is intended
				specifically for reporting to PEPFAR.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To see a Pepfar Report, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Reports</emphasis>
				from the main screen. This will open the Reports screen.
				From the Reports screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Pepfar Report</emphasis>
				. The Pepfar Report screen will open. It looks like
				this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/ReportPepfar.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>ReportPepfar.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>You should select:</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						The start and end date for the report, by
						clicking a date on each calendar.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						The cutoff age for paediatric patients
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						The cutoff age for the young paediatric patients
						subset
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				Then, select
				<emphasis role="strong">View Report</emphasis>
				to see the Pepfar Report for the period you have
				specified. Select
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				to return to the Reports Screen.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The report will open in a Report Viewer. You can now
				print or save the report. For information about this,
				please see Printing and Saving Reports.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Patient Defaulters</title>
			<simpara>
				A Patient Defaulters Report is a report of all patients
				who have not picked up their packages within a
				user-specified number of days from their expected
				appointment date.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To see a Patient Defaulters Report report, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Reports</emphasis>
				from the main screen. This will open the Reports screen.
				From the Reports screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Patient Defaulters Report
				</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The next screen to open will be the Patient Defaulters
				screen. It looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/ReportPatientDefaulters.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>ReportPatientDefaulters.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				From this screen, you will need to select the
				distribution point for which you wish to generate a
				patient defaulters report. You can also edit the minimum
				number of days a patient must be to be considered a
				defaulter, and the maximum number of days late a patient
				should be to be shown on this report. Then, select
				<emphasis role="strong">View Report</emphasis>
				to see a Patient Defaulters report for the distribution
				point you have specified (or
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				to return to the Reports Screen).
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The report will open in a Report Viewer. You can now
				print or save the report. For information about this,
				please see Printing and Saving Reports.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Daily Dispensing Totals Report</title>
			<simpara>
				A Daily Dispensing Totals Report shows the number of
				patients seen and the number of ARV drugs (in
				containers, rounded up) dispensed each day for a month.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To see a Daily Dispensing Totals Report, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Reports</emphasis>
				from the main screen. This will open the Reports screen.
				From the Reports screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Daily Dispensing Totals
				</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The next screen to open will be the Daily Dispensing
				Totals screen. It looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/ReportDailyDispensingTotals.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>ReportDailyDispensingTotals.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				From this screen, you will need to select the
				distribution point for which you wish to generate daily
				dispensing totals, as well as the month and year. Then,
				select
				<emphasis role="strong">View Report</emphasis>
				to see a Daily Dispensing Totals report for the
				distribution point, month and year you have specified
				(or
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				to return to the Reports Screen).
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The report will open in a Report Viewer. You can now
				print or save the report. For information about this,
				please see Printing and Saving Reports.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Monthly Stock Receipts</title>
			<simpara>
				A Monthly Stock Receipt report is a list of all the
				stock that has arrived at the pharmacy during a certain
				month.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To see a Monthly Stock Receipt, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Reports</emphasis>
				from the main screen. This will open the Reports screen.
				From the Reports screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Monthly Stock Receipts
				</emphasis>
				.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The next screen to open will be the Monthly Stock
				Receipts screen. It looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/ReportMonthlyStockReceipts.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>ReportMonthlyStockReceipts.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				From this screen, you will need to select the month for
				which you wish to generate the report. Do this by
				selecting the month and year from the drop-down lists.
				Then, select
				<emphasis role="strong">View Report</emphasis>
				to see a Monthly Stock Receipt report for the period you
				have specified (or
				<emphasis role="strong">Close</emphasis>
				to return to the Reports Screen).
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The report will open in a Report Viewer. You can now
				print or save the report. For information about this,
				please see Printing and Saving Reports.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Monthly Clinic Indicator Report</title>
			<simpara>
				The Monthly Clinic Indicator Report shows statistics for
				each clinic, for a certain month. This is divided into
				paediatric and adult patient statistics. The report also
				contains regimen information, which relies on correctly
				defined Drug Groups (see Drug Groups)
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To see a Monthly Clinic Indicator Report , select
				<emphasis role="strong">Reports</emphasis>
				from the main screen. This will open the Reports screen.
				From the Reports screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Monthly Clinic Indicator Report
				</emphasis>
				. The Monthly Clinic Indicator Report screen will open.
				It looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/ReportMonthlyClinicIndicator.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>
							ReportMonthlyClinicIndicator.png
						</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				You should select a distribution point from the
				drop-down list, and also set values for the parameters:
			</simpara>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Minimum Days Late, which is the shortest length
						of time that must elapse after a patient was
						expected to collect a package, for them to be
						considered a defaulter.
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<simpara>
						Cutoff Age For Paediatric Patients
					</simpara>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<simpara>
				Then, select
				<emphasis role="strong">View Report</emphasis>
				to see a Monthly Clinic Indicator Report for the
				distribution point and parameters you have specified (or
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				to return to the Reports Screen).
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The report will open in a Report Viewer. You can now
				print or save the report. For information about this,
				please see Printing and Saving Reports.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Patients Expected On A Day</title>
			<simpara>
				This report shows a list of patients expected on a given
				day. The list is generated by comparing the next
				appointment date for each patient with the date chosen
				on the Patients Expected On A Day screen.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To see a list of patients expected on a day, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Reports</emphasis>
				from the main screen. This will open the Reports screen.
				From the Reports screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Patients Expected On A Day
				</emphasis>
				. The Patients Expected On A Day screen will open. It
				looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/ReportPatientsExpected.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>ReportPatientsExpected.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				From this screen, you will need to select a distribution
				point and also a date for the report. Select the
				distribution point from the drop-down list. To specify a
				date range, select the month and year from the drop-down
				lists, and clicking a date on each calender. Then,
				select
				<emphasis role="strong">View Report</emphasis>
				to see a Patients Expected On A Day list for the date
				and distribution point you have specified.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Select
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				to return to the Reports Screen, or
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				to remain at this screen but clear the information
				(distribution point and date range) you have entered.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The report will open in a Report Viewer. You can now
				print or save the report. For information about this,
				please see Printing and Saving Reports.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>ARV Drug Usage Report</title>
			<simpara>
				The ARV Drug Usage report shows, for a user-specified
				set of drugs, how many units of each drug were dispensed
				per day. This is displayed for a user-specified date
				range.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To see an ARV Drug Usage report, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Reports</emphasis>
				from the main screen. This will open the Reports screen.
				From the Reports screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">ARV Drug Usage Report</emphasis>
				. The ARV Drug Usage report screen will open. It looks
				like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/ReportARVDrugUsage.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>ReportARVDrugUsage.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				From this screen, you will need to select the drugs to
				include (up to a maximum of 11), and also a date range
				for the report. To select the drugs, click the check
				boxes in the Drugs list. To specify a date range, click
				a date on each calender. Then, select
				<emphasis role="strong">View Report</emphasis>
				to see an ARV Drug Usage report for the period you have
				specified. Select
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				to return to the Reports Screen, or
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				to remain at this screen but clear the information
				(drugs and date range) you have entered.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The report will open in a Report Viewer. You can now
				print or save the report. For information about this,
				please see Printing and Saving Reports.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>
				Monthly Report of Receipts and Issues of ARV Drugs
			</title>
			<simpara>
				This report shows a record of stock levels, receipts and
				issues for a certain month at a certain clinic.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To see a Monthly Report of Receipts and Issues of ARV
				Drugs, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Reports</emphasis>
				from the main screen. This will open the Reports screen.
				From the Reports screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Monthly Report of Receipts and Issuse of ARV Drugs
				</emphasis>
				. The Monthly Stock Overview screen will open. It looks
				like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/ReportMonthlyReceipts.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>ReportMonthlyReceipts.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				You should select the distribution point, month and year
				from the drop-down lists. Then, select
				<emphasis role="strong">View Report</emphasis>
				to see a Monthly Report of Receipts and Issuse of ARV
				Drugs for the month and distribution point you have
				specified. Select
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				to return to the Reports Screen, or
				<emphasis role="strong">Clear</emphasis>
				to remain at this screen but clear the information (
				distribution point and month) you have entered.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The report will open in a Report Viewer. You can now
				print or save the report. For information about this,
				please see Printing and Saving Reports.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Transaction Log Report</title>
			<simpara>
				The Transaction Log Report shows all logged transactions
				(deletions and stock destructions). This is displayed
				for a user-specified date range.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				To see an Transaction Log Report, select
				<emphasis role="strong">Reports</emphasis>
				from the main screen. This will open the Reports screen.
				From the Reports screen, select
				<emphasis role="strong">
					Transaction Log Report
				</emphasis>
				. The Transaction Log Report report screen will open. It
				looks like this:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/ReportTransactionLog.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>ReportTransactionLog.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				From this screen, you will need to select a date range
				for the report. To specify a date range, click a date on
				each calender. Then, select
				<emphasis role="strong">View Report</emphasis>
				to see a Transaction Log Report for the period you have
				specified. Select
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				to return to the Reports Screen.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				The report will open in a Report Viewer. You can now
				print or save the report. For information about this,
				please see Printing and Saving Reports.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Printing and Saving Reports</title>
			<simpara>
				Reports will open in a window like the one below:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/JasperViewerEG.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>JasperViewerEG.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				You can view the report in this screen, and also print
				or save it. In the image below, the left button is the
				save button, and the right button is the print button.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/JasperViewerPrintSaveButtons.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>
							JasperViewerPrintSaveButtons.png
						</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<sect2>
				<title>To print the report:</title>
				<simpara>
					Click on the printer button in the icon bar at the
					top of the viewer. The button is second from the
					left. This will bring up a screen that will let you
					choose a printer and associated settings. It looks
					like this:
				</simpara>

				<simpara>
					<inlinemediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata
								fileref="images/JasperViewerPrint.png" align="center" />
						</imageobject>
						<textobject>
							<phrase>JasperViewerPrint.png</phrase>
						</textobject>
					</inlinemediaobject>
				</simpara>

			</sect2>
			<sect2>
				<title>To save the report:</title>
				<simpara>
					Click on the save button in the icon bar at the top
					of the viewer. The button is the first from the left
					hand side. This will bring up the following screen:
				</simpara>

				<simpara>
					<inlinemediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata
								fileref="images/JasperViewerSave.png" align="center" />
						</imageobject>
						<textobject>
							<phrase>JasperViewerSave.png</phrase>
						</textobject>
					</inlinemediaobject>
				</simpara>

				<simpara>
					You can select the file format in which the report
					should be saved from the drop-down list (shown
					dropped down in the image). The recommended format
					is PDF, which can be read by Adobe Acrobat and a
					number of free viewers, such as xpdf, but cannot be
					modified. Choose a file format, and give the file a
					name. Also navigate to the place you want to save
					the file, and then press
					<emphasis role="strong">Save</emphasis>
					.
				</simpara>

			</sect2>
		</sect1>
	</chapter>
	<chapter>
		<title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
		<simpara>
			This section offers answers to some frequently asked
			questions regarding the day-to-day use of the system. If you
			have a problem that you cannot find a solution to in the
			rest of the manual, you may be able to solve it by refering
			to this section. However, if you are unsuccessful, please
			call the Cell-Life iDART Helpdesk, where one of the system's
			developers will assist you.
		</simpara>

		<sect1>
			<title>Using the Patient Search</title>
			<simpara>
				Pressing
				<emphasis role="strong">Patient Search</emphasis>
				will bring up a list of the IDs and names of all the
				patients in the system. If you enter a chapter of a
				Patient ID or name, the system will shorten the list by
				hiding all those patients whose names and IDs do not
				contain the characters you have entered. You can also
				scroll through the list of patients using the arrows on
				the right hand side. For example, if the system has
				patients ABC112, ABC122 and ABC123, entering ABC will
				not hide any of the patient IDs, but entering ABC11 will
				hide the second and third IDs as only the first (ABC112)
				can match ABC11. Note that the search is not case
				sensitive, ie. AB, ab and Ab are the same.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				This screenshot shows the Patient Search screen
				displaying all the patients in the system:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							fileref="images/PatientSearchFull.png" align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>PatientSearchFull.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				This screenshot shows the Patient Search screen
				displaying only patients with IDs or names containing
				ab:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/PatientSearchAB.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>PatientSearchAB.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				Note that most patient search screens will only allow
				you to search patients whose account status is
				<emphasis>active</emphasis>
				. For example, you can't add a prescription for an
				inactive patient, so there will not be inactive patients
				in the search on the Add/Update Prescription screen. The
				exception is the Update Patient screen, where you can
				search through all patients, active or inactive
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				When you have found the patient you are looking for,
				click on the ID in the list. This will close the Patient
				Search screen and bring up the relevant information
				about the patient whose ID you selected. Clicking
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				from the Patient Search screen will close the screen but
				not bring up information about any patients.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
		<sect1>
			<title>Using the Drug Search</title>
			<simpara>
				Pressing
				<emphasis role="strong">Drug Search</emphasis>
				will bring up a list of the drugs in the system, and
				their pack sizes. If you enter a chapter of a drug name,
				the system will shorten the list by hiding all those
				drugs whose names do not contain the characters you have
				entered. You can also scroll through the list of drugs
				using the arrows on the right hand side. Note that the
				search is not case sensitive, ie. AB, ab and Ab are the
				same.
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				This screenshot shows the Drug Search screen displaying
				all the drugs in the system:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/DrugSearchAll.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>DrugSearchAll.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				This screenshot shows the Drug Search screen displaying
				only drugs whose name contains Nev:
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/DrugSearchNev.png"
							align="center" />
					</imageobject>
					<textobject>
						<phrase>DrugSearchNev.png</phrase>
					</textobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>
			</simpara>

			<simpara>
				When you have found the drug you are looking for, click
				on the entry in the list. This will close the Drug
				Search screen and bring up the relevant information
				about the drug you selected. Clicking
				<emphasis role="strong">Cancel</emphasis>
				from the Drug Search screen will close the screen but
				not bring up information about any drug.
			</simpara>

		</sect1>
	</chapter>
</book>
